Hwee Shan Wong

Software Developer



About me

Hi, my name is Hwee and currently a software engineer in Natwest Group. I am passionate about developing tools and products to boost engineering experience for other engineers. I have experience in delivering microservices using the twelve-factor app methodology. I have also worked on implementing infrastructure solutions and services.

Grew up trilingual (English, Mandarin,

Skills



Contact



✓ hweeshan_wong@hotmail.com

+44 7424 586 826

HweeWong

Experience

Software Engineer

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | since April 2018

- Automated the onboarding process to developer tools. Reduced cycle time from 48 hrs to 5 mins.
- Delivered Spring Boot Java microservices in event-driven architecture and have deep understanding of the system design.
- Collaborated closely with customers/SMEs in agile development.
- >50% reduction in cycle time from development to release
- · Cultivated the culture of BDD, TDD within the team which enhanced system reliability and team's devops metrics.
- Presented proof of concepts for different IAM integration of tools.
- Led migration work for on-prem SaaS product.

Technology Service Analyst

Natwest Group, Edinburgh | Sep 2017 - Apr 2018

- · Migrated server data from bespoke tools to ServiceNow CMDB for better consolidation of data within the enterprise.
- · Embedded agile methodology for the project through creation of short-term, manageable goals and Kanban dashboards.
- Improved communications plans with stakeholders to ensure transparency and effective communication.

Chemical Engineer

Merck, Sharp & Dohme (MSD), Newcastle | Aug 2015 - Sep 2016

- Supported technical operations in solid-dose tablet production facility and operated within GMP standards.
- Led incidents/deviations investigations to identify root causes using Lean Six Sigma methodologies.
- Generated technical memorandums for process improvements. Implementation of new design reduced operation downtime.

Education

MEng Chemical Engineering with Industrial Experience, University of Manchester

Sep 2013 - Jun 2017

First Class Honors

A Levels, Taylor's College Jan 2012 - Jun 2013

4A* in Chemistry, Biology, Physics, Mathematics



Contributions

Women In Tech Secretariat

Actively supporting gender balance within workplace. Running python workshops to promote engineering.

STEM Ambassador STV Big Scot Quiz

Encouraging students to appreciate Science. Technology, Engineering and Math (STEM) subjects by engaging students in interesting experiments concurrently in and sharing work experience.

Volunteer

Volunteered to assist and coordinate the running of a major, high-profile charity event that was held Edinburgh and Glasgow which raised £35,000.